xinyuan zhao

7808850699 | xinyuan7@ualberta.ca

EDUCATION

University of Alberta, Canada

Sep 2018 - Dec 2022

Computer major (Specialization in Computing Science) Bachelor

Major courses: program development in C language, data structure, Android software development, operating system, computer network;

SKILLS LIST

Proficient in using basic data structures (arrays, linked lists, binary trees, etc.) and basic algorithms (searching, sorting, recursion, etc.);

Proficient in writing scripts in Python;

Proficient in writing SQL statements;

Familiar with the use of basic Linux operating system;

Project Experience

Database Manager Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

Job Description: This project is to develop a database management program. Users can visualize database tables and create, delete, and modify database tables;

Personal work and results:

- Use Python and MongoDB to implement database data calls;
- Use multiple preset SQL statements to MongoDB access and modify data;

Android software development

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

Project Description: This project is a group course project that uses relevant knowledge to develop an Android application to help users track habits.

Personal work and results:

- Learn to apply object programming ideas, design patterns, development of iterative models and other software processes.
- Use Java language for development, log on to delete and modify habit.
- The project code can be accessed from this link:https://github.com/CMPUT301F21T08/HabitTracker

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Majorel China May 2021 - Aug 2021

Business analyst Shanghai (China)

What I do in this company is data analysis. For example, analyze the sales of some fast-selling brands, and analyze the reasons for the increase or decrease in sales. My main responsibility is to write weekly reports and monthly summaries.

During the internship, sql, excel and ppt are mainly used. I learned about the application of sql and the application

of data, which are different from the daily school learning.

Undefined definitions of a data can have a large impact on the results. Misattribution can also occur. In the process of continuous optimization of the new definition, it is beneficial for the company to increase sales, optimize production structure and marketing strategy. It also strengthens and consolidates the knowledge that I have learned on a daily basis.

Summary

I am friendly, sincere, meticulous, dedicated, have a strong sense of responsibility, learning ability and adaptability, like to talk with others, love life. The most prominent character label is seriousness, with the characteristics of calm and introverted, good at thinking and research. Have good communication and coordination skills, be good at responding, be able to quickly adapt to the new environment, be good at execution and have a team spirit, and can withstand high-intensity work.

SKILLS, CERTIFICATIONS & OTHERS

• Skills: Python, Java, SQL, PowerPoint, Excel, Word,

· Languages: English, Mandarin